Er. RAHUL KUMAR GUPTA

Scrum Master

Email: guptarh9@gmail.com Contact No.: 7060874201 Skype: rahul.gupta9400

Address: Karol Bagh, New Delhi, 110005, INDIA

LinkedIn:https://in.linkedin.com/in/rahul-gupta-436a50124

<u>Summary</u>

Results-oriented software developer and research professional with 6+ **years** experience in both development and research positions. I make it my goal to create software with the user in mind, creating applications with a useable and intuitive user interface experience. I also understand the importance of creating highly readable and easily maintainable source code. I am constantly striving to learn new technologies and look to ways to better myself in this rapidly changing industry. I Started my Career as **Scrum Master** to till now I Worked Individually and with Team, Self Learn and Implement.

Certificate

Scrum Master Certification from Master of Project Academy.

Technical skills

Languages: Swift, Objective-C, Java, JavaScript, C Language, SQLite, HTML, React.JS

IDE: Xcode, Eclipse, Android Studio, Dreamweaver, Visual Studio, **Jira**.

Framework: ARKit, (ML/AI) (AR/VR), TensorFlow, React Native, Cocoa Touch, WebKit,

AVFoundation, Fastlane etc.

Game Engine: Unity3D, Unreal Engine 4.

Development: Agile with scrum methodology

Technologies: Restful web services, Cocoa Pods, AWS, GitHub, etc.

Payment Gateways - CCAvenue, PayPal.

Projects in Swift Programming Language with Link:

- 1) GeoTrack-GeoRadius Tracking (georadius.com) https://apps.apple.com/in/app/geotrack-georadius/id1231716769
- 2) Fashom Personal Styling App (<u>fashom.com</u>) https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/fashom-personal-styling-app/id792574857?mt=8
 - 3) Whim event app (Only working in Us) (https://www.whim.nyc/) https://itunes.apple.com/cn/app/whim-trending-event-guide-in-nyc/id1053832033?l=en&mt=8
 - 4) Twassel (online recharge (mobile, internet, shopping cards), buy cart, other information related to home and government services) https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/twassel-%D8%AA%D9%88%D8%A7%D8%B5%D9%84/id1390994173?mt=8
 - 5) SHAMEL 90800 (Exclusive services that allowed customers to buy prepaid cards (ebay, visa shopping card, cashU etc.)) https://itunes.apple.com/in/app/shamel-90800/id877992808?mt=8
 - 6) Jroot Pro (Live Audio streaming using SoundCloud and live radio with download)

https://itunes.apple.com/in/app/jroot-radio-pro/id767607194?mt=8

- 7) Jroot (Live audio streaming using SoundCloud) https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/jroot/id1242203422?mt=8
- 8) Nitnem audio https://itunes.apple.com/in/app/nitnem-audio/id965130739?mt=8
- 9) Fatch TV https://itunes.apple.com/in/app/fatch-tv/id976944652?mt=8
- 10) BasketBall Quiz

https://itunes.apple.com/za/app/basketball-quiz/id1089423857?mt=8

Work experience

Scrum Master Toko | TokoRecharge

Dates Employed: 03/2019 – Present

Perform Scrum Master Role in Organisation to Handle team. Took Requirement from Product Owner and Divide key responsibilities to the Scrum Team.

Assist development team and Product Owner. Work with Agile Methodology

Empower Development team

Handle time to time work progress report.

Work to maximise return on Investment.

iOS Developer | React Native Developers

ClubJB.com

Dates Employed: 10/2017 - 12/2018

Perform Lead iOS | Swift Developer role in an enterprise. They work for their Clients as well as In House iOS app.

Projects are Completely Done in Swift Programming Language.

RESTful web services development with Alamofire. Works did Login, Logout and some JSON Parsing Who are get Data from server and manage it all with corresponding shows. As well as Working on React Native Technology to enhance Productivity for Organisation. Implement Payment Gateways Like - CCAvenue, PayPal.

iOS Developer Govern Technologies.

Dates Employed: 10/2016 – 10/2017

Performed in a Lead developer role on an enterprise iOS app for Clients. App allows employees to scan store inventory to display real time point of sale, e-commerce, and nightly data warehouse data. Featured remote device configuration by consuming Restful web services to pull down store specific app settings.

Whole Projects Complete in Swift Programming Language.

Application would allow user to choose there Fashion ideal and connect with chat. Allow the user and Fashion icon to connect both Rating, Reviews, ideas etc.

iOS Developer Iotasol Technologies.

Dates Employed: 01/2015 – 10/2016

Successfully started career with Iotasol Technologies and implement Some Projects individually without any kind of help other person. Started work with Objective-C and after 2 Project Star Work on Swift Programming Language.

Develop Some Quiz Games, Business Applications and Social Networking Application. These Application Allows Remote Notification for use of user and Admin. Framework Uses Cocoa Pods and individually also.

CocoaPods using such Frameworks and the frameworks are need to implement features in Applications SideMenuBar, API's and other kind of work done by Frameworks. Which are allow by cocoa pods

iPhone and iPad both working with Different Layout. Storyboard, XIB and By Programmatically done both differ layout show the view on both devices.

Education

CCS University

BCA (Bachelor of Computer Application)

U.PBoard

12th

U.PBoard

10th

Declaration

I hereby confirm that all the mentioned information is true and authentic to the best of my knowledge.